We're the most successful, best
performing stock in the world last year.
The decision to adopt Bitcoin as our
core treasury asset has been an absolute
game changanger for us over the past
year. During, you know, the depths of
despair when I was running my hotel
business, I was comforted by listening
to some podcasts that Michael Sailor was
on. This is a dilemma that I was
thinking about. The fact that
governments can just print them at will,
right? All the hard work that you put in
can be printed at will. A lot of people
see this playbook and be like, I want to
just copy this. They're like, this is
like a cheat sheet. So, a lot of people
come in, they're not their heart is not
in the right place, right? But they
claim that they're Bitcoin companies. I
have a view perhaps in public and
another one in private. Um I want the
one in private. We're in the first part
of this Bitcoin journey. This is phase
one. In phase one, we're in a gold rush.
During the gold rush, we want to secure
as much Bitcoin as we can of the Bitcoin
network. It's only 21 million. But then
in phase two when when is stage two
I'll share that during co during death.
We're joined today by Simon Garvich,
president of Metal Planet. We're talking
about the future of treasury holdings
for Bitcoin and the future of
hospitality linking with Bitcoin. Bonnie
Channing is joining us today. She's the
host of Bonnie Blockchain. Welcome to
the show, Simon. It's a pleasure to be
here. Thank you for having me. The
latest news that came in today, uh,
Metaplanet has reached almost 600k per
coin um in Bitcoin premium and the
article says that is way too high. Do
you think MNAV is a good metric for
Bitcoin Treasury company?
Well, there's lots of KPIs that have
been recently adopted. Uh BTC yield I
think is the perhaps the most important
one. Um tells you about your Bitcoin per
share and how quickly it's growing. It's
something that Sailor adopted. Um and
Bitcoin treasury companies now around
the world are are doing the same. So I
think one needs to look at various
metrics when they think about how a
company ought to be valued. Now MNAV is
your multiple your market cap plus your
debt enterprise value divided by your
Bitcoin holdings. And that's something
that you know will eb and flow with kind
of interest in your stock and um the
activities that you engage in. So I
think there's lots of reasons for why a
company should have a premium to its
NAV. Um and that for us I think how our
flywheel began um a year ago was that
because the taxation is very different
for those who want to buy Bitcoin
directly. If you're a Japanese retail
investor, you have to pay up to 55% as
personal income tax or you can buy a
listed rapper, a company like Metaplanet
that gives exposure in a taxefficient
manner. And so that started our flywheel
and I think what justifies an MNAV
really are numerous things and um most
importantly I think it's your ability to
increase your Bitcoin per share. So
we're one of the fastest growing
companies in the world now in terms of
growing our Bitcoin per share and you
know MNAV is is something which we're
very much focused on kind of maintaining
you know between sort of three to five
um you know we don't want to be selling
shares aggressively and and pushing the
stock down. Um but at the same time it's
a really great way for us to increase
Bitcoin per share on behalf of all of
our shareholders. I think in one of your
interviews you said the Japanese market
if they want Bitcoin exposure they kind
of have to go go through you right or is
it well there's there's various choices
so one can just go to a local exchange
and buy Bitcoin of course of course but
the problem there is that they're
exposed to the tax and so I think when
people realize they would like exposure
in a tax efficient manner and in a way
where they're able to outperform Bitcoin
Bitcoin obviously if you just buy
Bitcoin your your performance will be
Bitcoin Mhm. If you're in the US and you
buy an ETF, your performance um, you
know, by virtue of of an ETF, you know,
being aligned to the price of Bitcoin
will will never outperform Bitcoin. But
the beauty of a Bitcoin treasury
company, a company that is an operating
company that can utilize, you know, all
the capital market tools available, um,
equity issuances, um, you know, in time
convert issuances, prep equity
issuances, that's how you can actually
increase your Bitcoin per share. And
there are three metrics. Bitcoin per
share, BTC dollar gain, and BTC gain.
What are the differences? So BTC yield
is the change in Bitcoin per share from
one period uh to another. And so our
Bitcoin our BTC yield um so far this
year is about 190%. So we've increased
our Bitcoin per share by 190%. Basically
almost tripling our Bitcoin per share.
Now, BTC gain takes BTC yield and puts
it in kind of an absolute Bitcoin sense.
So, the math is taking your Bitcoin
holdings at the end of the last period
and you multiply by your BTC yield. And
so, for us this year, I think it's
around 3 and a half thousand Bitcoin
that we have generated through our
Bitcoin treasury operations after
considering dilution. and then take that
3,500 Bitcoin, multiply it by the
Bitcoin price, that gives you BTC dollar
gain. So it really converts into I
suppose a way for the traditional market
to understand, you know, how much value
is being created under the hood. And so
for us, we our BTC dollar gain this year
is about $400 million. And I like to
think of that about that as sort of like
a profit number. It isn't really profit,
but it does show the underlying value
that's being created. And so, take $400
million, annualize that, you know, for
the for the rest of the year, that could
be a billion dollars of BTC gain. And
so, what is a company worth that can
generate a billion dollars of value on
behalf of all shareholders on an annual
basis? And so I think you know the the
challenge right now is that traditional
finance has limited tools to value
companies. They look at things in you
know the the box which they've been
given. But Bitcoin treasury companies
can't be looked at in the same way right
we don't have substantial revenue to
speak of. We don't have um you know
earnings really to to speak of in the
traditional sense like an operating
company. And so one must look at other
tools and BTC yield, BTC gain, BTC
dollar gain are are some of those um
tools that uh I think companies will um
will be adopting and analysts will be
able to look at that and and understand
what's happening. Before we get your
philosophy on Bitcoin itself, which I
find very interesting, you probably have
some interesting views on that as well.
Um let's talk about your company
Metaplanet. It's been compared to Micro
Strategy. In fact, it's been dubbed the
strategy micro strategy of Asia. How
would you respond to that comparison?
Very honored and humbled by by that
comparison. Michael Sailor has been a
huge inspiration. Um I I often share
that during COVID during you know the
depths of despair when I was running my
hotel business. Um, I was comforted by
listening to some podcasts that that
Michael Sailor was on and just sharing
with with everyone, sharing with the
world his, you know, vision on how a
listed company can can pivot um and
embrace Bitcoin in a way that um wasn't
possible in the past. And so that really
gave me the inspiration to to pivot out
of the hotel business, which was already
struggling. So there wasn't really much
of a choice but there were many
directions that we could have taken and
the decision to adopt Bitcoin as our you
know core treasury asset has been an
absolute gamecher for us over the past
year. You must have reached some
resistance amongst your investors
initially when you wanted to start this
pivot objections to holding any asset
besides your core business especially
something as new and novel as Bitcoin.
How did you overcome these objections or
what was the conversation like at the
meeting? Yeah, you know, it's a I want
to say it's a blessing in disguise that
we weren't performing very well. It's
you know, it's sad to say, but we were a
company that was struggling. We we had
no choice um but to pivot. The board and
the shareholders at that time um you
know said to me, Simon, think of
something, anything that can save the
company. And so it wasn't like we had a
very difficult board meeting and there
were directors that were against the
idea. Um but I am brought back to years
ago when the company was doing fine and
I proposed to the board that we should
accept Bitcoin at our hotels. It seems
like a very simple thing to do, a very
you know easy kind of next step. But I
was kind of laughed out of the boardroom
at that point saying why would we risk
our business with something as
undesirable as Bitcoin? And so um you
know gave it up because
there was really no choice. Yeah. Um but
I did think in the future what would
there be an opportunity for us to be
able to bring Bitcoin back into you know
our core business and and we were able
to do that at the right time. Just based
on what you just said this is the
dilemma that I was thinking about. So
you have healthy companies with health
healthy cash flow and unhealthy company
that are struggling. Now the unhealthy
company might
turn themselves into Bitcoin treasury
company because I have nothing else. I
have nothing to lose and the upside is
huge. Now after they do that the stock
price shoot up and they outperform the
larger company with healthy cash flow.
How does this end?
Well, I think the amazing thing is
Bitcoin treasury companies are finding a
way to give exposure to investors who
otherwise may have found it difficult to
to get exposure. Everyone has a
securities account. They're able to buy
stocks and they're familiar buying
stocks, but there's an extra step
requiring people to open up a a crypto
exchange account. And you know there's
been numerous hacks in the past and I
think some people who um perhaps
concerned about that aspect of of
Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies um get put
off and then you have you know the
traditional investors that just can't
buy Bitcoin. Their funds don't allow
them to do so but they can buy listed
equities. And so I think this wonderful
innovation of a Bitcoin treasury company
is a gamecher. It's it's a black hole of
capital. It's a tidal wave of capital
that will be flowing into Bitcoin thanks
to Bitcoin treasury companies. Um, of
course, one I think needs to be very
careful about which Bitcoin treasury
company they select. Um, track record I
think will be increasingly important.
Um, you know, we have the benefit now of
a a long track record of 14 months. Um,
and strategy has a long track record now
of five years. Um, and it's important,
you know, what the CEO says. Um, are
they a Bitcoiner? Do they believe in
Bitcoin? Are they ever going to sell
their Bitcoin? Um, I'm reminded of I
went to this conference in Tokyo a
couple weeks ago, CLSA conference. They
they do a um a conference focused on
Japanese equities. And in the crowd,
someone asked me a question and said,
you know, what else are you going to buy
besides Bitcoin? And I apparently had
this really disgusted look on my face.
Um, which people captured and and shared
on social media. Um, but you know, no
one should ever doubt that MetaPlanet
would buy anything other than Bitcoin.
We'll only ever buy Bitcoin. We'll never
sell our Bitcoin. And that message is
also very clear uh from Michael Sailor.
And so I think if you're investing in a
Bitcoin treasury company, it needs to be
fully in and never sell and do
everything they can to accumulate more.
Could you show that face? It was like
again.
Love it. She does a good impression of
that face as well, but you know, offline
usually. Usually when I'm talking to
her, annoying, but um show it to us.
That's exactly what that's exactly the
face she makes when I talk to her. Uh
Simon, can you tell us about the initial
stages of this pivot? You said you were
a struggling hospitality company. How
did you finance the acquisition of
Bitcoin initially and how did the
financing, you know, evolve over the
last couple of years? Sure. Um so we had
a series of hotels and during that
initial meeting when we discussed moving
into to Bitcoin we made the decision uh
to sell um hotels um so a lot of the
sale from the hotels that gave us the
initial capital um we also raised
capital from um some like-minded
investors at that time um and some of
the investors are at this conference um
and so UTXO management the sponsors of
the Bitcoin conference they became one
of our early shareholders ers and we got
a tremendous board and a lot of the
board members who joined us also
invested in that um that effectively
private placement at that time. Um so we
bought our initial round of of Bitcoin
um at the beginning of last year and
then we proceeded to do a rights issue
and a rights issue is as you're familiar
uh you buy the company offers new shares
for existing shareholders to purchase
and so for every share that was
outstanding we offered one new share for
ex existing shareholders to purchase and
traditionally a rights issue is
perceived very negatively. a company
that has a rights issue is is
struggling. They they need to raise
capital on an urgent basis to survive.
Um but in retrospect, it was the best
thing we could have done. We had 13
14,000 shareholders fill out a huge
stack of documents to give us money to
buy Bitcoin. And that created, I think,
the initial connection between our
Japanese shareholders and the company
because they gave us the money that we
used to buy Bitcoin. If you go into the
market now and buy shares of any
company, you're buying shares from
someone else who is selling. But when
you subscribe for new shares, that cash
comes into the company and you think as
a shareholder, wow, that's my money
going towards the company buying
Bitcoin. And so we did that. That was
last summer. Um we raised um I believe
around 60 70 million US at that time. Um
and then we proceeded at the end of the
year to issue our first moving strike
warrant. And the moving strike warrant
is Japan's answer to the US at the money
equity offering. And so in the US, it's
very straightforward for a company to
sell new shares directly into the
market, which is what strategy is doing.
Um but that isn't possible for us in
Japan. And so we have a moving strike
warrant structure. Um that's issued to
um a partner who then uh effectively
sells shares in the market, uses the
cash to exercise the warrants, and they
get new shares issued which they return.
The ultimate result is exactly the same,
but we've we've managed to raise a lot
of capital um by using the moving strike
warrant. And so we did one in December
and then our most recent one, which we
launched in February uh just closed um
just finished exercising last week. We
announced accordingly and we raised
about $600 million of equity. And so the
pace of capital raising now is is really
speeding up. And the larger you get, the
more shares you can issue and the more
Bitcoin you can buy. And so we you know
plan to continue with um you know the
kind of the at the money equivalent and
then in time again strategy has made it
very clear for everyone what the
playbook is. Yes. And so we can issue
converts perhaps in the future. We can
issue preferred equity uh perhaps in the
future. But right now we're very much
focused on our equity phase. Um that's
the most efficient. That's permanent
capital. Capital you never have to repay
and we can buy Bitcoin with that.
back to what you were talking about. Um,
obviously Michael Sailor and you, you
guys are Bitcoiners and the company,
Bitcoin Treasury companies are supported
by all Bitcoiners. Now, a lot of people
see this playbook and be like, I want to
just copy this. This is what you're the
most successful, best performing stock
in the world last year, right? They're
like, oh, this is like a cheat sheet.
So, a lot of people come in, they're not
their heart is not in the right place,
right? But they claim that they're
Bitcoin companies. What is your view on
that?
Well, I uh I have a view perhaps in in
public and another one in private. Um I
want the one in private given this is a
public channel. Um I would say high
level it's great that more companies are
adopting a Bitcoin standard. I think
that should apply not just to struggling
companies like ours was, but successful
companies that have a lot of cash
sitting there doing nothing. Yes. Now,
there's always going to be bad players
that see this as a quick get-rich quick
scheme, and they may say, "Okay, if
Bitcoin is something that can make my
stock price go up, then why should I not
do the same?" I think investors are
smart and as more and more Bitcoin
treasury companies appear, it'll be
easier for investors to be able to
compare and contrast. And there are
quite a few platforms that I've seen now
that do a really good job of um, you
know, monitoring all the different uh,
Bitcoin treasury companies on a BTC
yield basis and Bitcoin per share basis,
etc. And so it'll come out in the wash,
right? The companies that execute and
that are focused and disciplined, they
will command a greater premium um, than
those that that don't. Um, you know,
there are I've seen I've seen a company
recently, you know, announcing that they
sold their Bitcoin. I thought to myself,
that's that's a bit silly. Um, they
wanted to book some profit in the last
quarter and they announced, you know,
months ago that they were buying Bitcoin
and now if you start to sell your
Bitcoin, then you lose credibility.
People aren't going to buy you um as a
way to get exposure to more and more
Bitcoin over time. And so I think there
will be some differentiation over time
and it'll be clear for investors which
ones they want to back for specific
reasons. Um but yes, I think there are
various motives that exist for for
people as they um look to buy Bitcoin on
their balance sheet. Is there a price of
Bitcoin at which you would stop buying
or acquiring Bitcoin or at least slow
down the acquisition of Bitcoin?
Absolutely not. I think the Bitcoin so
if it goes to go up forever David 500k
next week you would you would buy more
and ignore the 5x appreciation over
in this hypothetical example one week. I
love your hypothetical example. What if
Bitcoin went to a trillion dollars by
tomorrow? Well then one must think
perhaps that's overvalued in that
moment. Um but um I mean we we plan to
keep buying Bitcoin forever. Again,
Michael Sailor likes to say that he
wants to buy the top all the time. You
know, we're competing with him to to buy
that top. But as we know today, you
know, we're we're kind of at all-time
highs again. And you know, Bitcoin is a
very special asset that has um you know,
interesting supply and demand mechanics.
And Bitcoin is something that's going to
continue to go up over time as more and
more the world um takes notice. Now, if
your question was when we're going to
sell our Bitcoin, again, that's that's
never. We want our shareholders to make
the decision when they'd like to buy and
sell our shares. We want to be a perfect
leverage proxy for Bitcoin. And the best
thing that we can do is remain focused
and disciplined and and not change that
plan, not make people wonder or be
concerned if something happens in the
markets that will suddenly change our
kind of perspective or point of view.
You know how Michael talks about um MSTR
is 1.5x leveraged Bitcoin. Now, a lot of
people, a lot of investors, they assume
that when Bitcoin hits all-time high,
MSTR or other Bitcoin treasury companies
should also hit all-time high. Why is it
not the case? We hit all-time high. Not
not you, but like other
companies, I think it's important to
maintain a long-term view. And so in the
case of of strategy, you know, the share
price today is maybe where it was four
or five months ago, but the big
difference is they have significantly
more Bitcoin per share. The company is
significantly more valuable today, even
if the share price may not reflect that,
right? But what I'm saying is the
public, they don't really understand
Bitcoin per share. Like how should they
look at it? Let's say you're talking to
uh my grandma who's 70, 80 years old.
How do you break it down to her?
Well, if your if your grandma's 70 or 80
years old, I I guess I can't say take a
long-term view. Um, but she can take a
long-term view for for you know, her
kids and for you, etc. It is, you know,
we're in the first part of this Bitcoin
journey. This is phase one. In phase
one, we're in a gold rush. During the
gold rush, we want to secure as much
Bitcoin as we can of the Bitcoin
network. There's only 21 million and
Strategy now has more Bitcoin than any
other public company. it will be very
difficult for anyone to catch up. Um
we'd like to be a firm number two. Um
but then in phase two when you know
Bitcoin price is significantly higher.
You know I think that is when the price
will begin to really reflect in a lot of
these public companies and so there's
you know supply demand mechanics.
There's Bitcoin price is very volatile.
The stocks are volatile. Um you
companies are executing their
fundraising. you know during this phase
one just needs to realize that um you
know the stock price may not necessarily
reflect the underlying value. um you
know the case of companies like Amazon
right it it underperformed for a long
long time as the company was growing you
know people knew how much revenue was um
you know was rising in the company but
they you know they were too much they
were too focused on on profit and there
wasn't much profit in the early days
because everything was being reinvested
into you know into advertising and
marketing and and growing the network
and so I think anyone who buys a Bitcoin
treasury company should not be doing it
on a very short-term basis in the same
way that if you buy Bitcoin you also
shouldn't be looking at it on a on a
very short-term basis. But the medium to
long-term Bitcoin treasury companies
will absolutely outperform Bitcoin
because they have this ability to grow
their Bitcoin per share. You buy shares
Bitcoin Treasury company. You let the
companies do the hard work. They're
doing the Bitcoin Treasury operations.
They're increasing Bitcoin per share.
And then you wake up again a year, two,
three, five from now and all of a sudden
your exposure to Bitcoin is is that much
more.
How much of domestic currency
performance how much does that impact
your new strategy for acquiring Bitcoin?
So as you know the yen has been
depreciating versus the dollar and other
currency baskets over the last 15 20
years. Had that not been the case would
you have still made this pivot?
Absolutely. I think, you know, Bitcoin
is this apex monetary asset that is, you
know, it's it's you can't there's
nothing else out there that is that is
as compelling. Um, if you're in a market
though where the currency is declining,
I mean, the US is a is a prime example.
A lot of people talk about the the US
and the money printing and, you know,
the debt burden that uh the country is
under. Um, Japan is quite similar. A lot
of the G7 nations are exactly the same.
So, Japan is the most indebted nation as
a percentage of GDP. Um, and it's it's
significant and you know, people's
purchasing power of the the yen is, you
know, has declined um significantly. Um,
most people who, you know, proudly could
go to Hawaii on vacation now, you know,
can't go anymore because, you know, the
yen has has weakened substantially. Um,
but I don't think this is a a comment
necessarily on the yen or the dollar.
It's just fiat currencies. Um the fact
that governments can just print them at
will, right? All the hard work that you
put in can be printed at will, yeah,
isn't the best long-term store value.
Just a quick followup. So the
understanding that Bitcoin protects
against inflation is well is well
understood. Yes. How about deflation? So
as you know, Japan has experienced
deflation throughout the 2000s and late
90s after the real estate crash.
um if my if the purchasing power of my
cash were to increase over time, which
is what deflation is, what then is the
thesis or need for something like
Bitcoin in that environment?
Very very esoteric. Um well, I you know,
prices have begun to to rise again.
Sure. I think we had an incredible you
know, asset bubble in Japan. Um you
know, fueled by reconstruction after the
war. So, Japan, I remember when I was
living there in the 80s that uh Japan
people writing books about Japan being
number one. I do hope Japan, you know,
returns to that position at some point.
Um, but uh yeah, it was is really price
is declining from an absolute incredible
peak. Inflation has returned. Um, but I
suppose if you're in an environment
where the value of your money goes up
over time, sort of a deflationary
environment, then um then maybe it's
less obvious to buy something like
Bitcoin. Um but Bitcoin is just it's
it's finite in a way that even a you
know a currency which is appreciating um
is not going to is not going to see in
the same way. So, uh, Bitcoin can stand
on its own and compared to the money
printing and the inflation that we're
seeing around the globe, uh, again,
there isn't a better thing that you can
purchase to store your value,
having that much Bitcoin, right? How do
you protect the Bitcoin? You know,
that's I think the reasons why a Bitcoin
treasury company is interesting is it it
creates it removes a lot of the hurdles
um to own Bitcoin. Um, and as we as we
shared earlier, it's you know, if you
can lose your private keys and you lose
your Bitcoin, it's not the same as
calling up your bank when you've got
your password and you get your money
back. Um, it's it's something that's
that that's that's fine. You know, it's
it's final. You never get it back. And
so, if if you invest in a Bitcoin
treasury company or even invest in an
ETF, you can sleep better at night
knowing that, you know, it's still going
to be there in the morning. Um, a lot of
Bitcoiners, they haven't told their
their wives or their husbands or their
children about their private keys. And,
you know, if they, god forbid, you know,
pass away, then again, their Bitcoin may
be maybe gone forever. And so, you know,
as as a company ourselves, we're very
much focused on transparency. You know,
we publish all of our public addresses.
It's on our dashboard. We think for us,
that's that's incredibly important to
gain the trust of, you know, the
investment community and and our
shareholders. Um, in Japan, we're
required by law to custody our Bitcoin
with licensed thirdparty custodians. And
so that's what we do. And as we acquire
more Bitcoin, we're adding more
custodians to the list. And so we want
to make sure that our Bitcoin is is
secure, best-in-class custodians, and
distributed across um, you know, any
number of of custodians at any one time.
Back to David's question earlier. Um, if
a com if a company says, "I'm a Bitcoin
treasury company, but they trade, let's
say they buy low and sell high, and
they're so good at this." How does that
destroy this whole system that works
beautifully? Like Michael Sailor came up
with this playbook like you said, but if
I sell, if I ever sell my Bitcoin, um
except for my investors being very
disappointed, what else is going to
happen? You're not really a Bitcoin
treasury company. I think if you're
trading your Bitcoin, you could be a
Bitcoin hedge fund, and there's plenty
of investment vehicles that give you
exposure to that. Um, I know there are
vehicles that earn a yield um, you know,
on various trading strategies that
relate to Bitcoin, but that's different
fundamentally to a Bitcoin treasury
company. We need to increase our our
Bitcoin per share um, over time and and
that's done by constantly accumulating
Bitcoin um, and not selling it. And
earlier you said we are at stage one,
right? This is the wild west. This is
the gold rush and we should wait for
stage two. When is stage two?
Stage two is probably maybe three to
five years from now, maybe five to seven
years from now. You know, it's a time
when there's, you know, massive Bitcoin
adoption around the globe. Bitcoin
prices north of a million dollars, maybe
it's $5 million. It's at a time when,
you know, banks are properly custodying
Bitcoin. And so now, if you're, you
know, if you own treasuries, you own a
stock portfolio, if you own real estate,
you can deposit that with a bank and
they'll lend you money against it. Right
now, it's not so possible to to do that
in the Bitcoin space. And I know many
banks now finally said, "We're going to
custody Bitcoin." But time will tell
when they actually do and offer you an
interest rate against your Bitcoin
that's attractive. But in phase two,
people will be able to use this pristine
balance sheet of Bitcoin. you know, I
hope we'll have trillions of dollars of
Bitcoin on our balance sheet and we'll
be able to deposit that with, you know,
a major bank and they'll lend us money
cheaply and we can use that cash to then
acquire businesses um that are, you
know, in our case focused on the Bitcoin
ecosystem. It could be getting a digital
banking license or buying a regional
bank and, you know, offering Bitcoin
related services to um you know, to our
customers. But it's incredibly exciting
in that second phase because in that
second phase there is so much that one
can do with you know pristine Bitcoin on
their balance sheets. Why aren't hotels
accepting their room charges in Bitcoin
right now? And would that change? Would
you spend your Bitcoin if I'm being paid
in Bitcoin and it becomes a currency?
Bing. I wouldn't one night I wouldn't
spend my Bitcoin. Why not? What? The
Bitcoin pizza story. Yeah. You end up
paying for a room and Bitcoin goes to a
million dollars. It was a very expensive
room you paid for. Yeah. That's in
hindsight, but you don't know what's
going to happen to the price tomorrow.
Is that why people don't use Bitcoin as
a medium of exchange universally right
now because everyone has this belief.
You You probably want to spend the
weaker currency
potentially. Yeah. And so spend your
Ethereum and other stuff that that you
may have in your portfolio. Oh, let's
talk about Ethereum.
But would you see a time in which not
just Bitcoin, but let's say a stable
coin being used for hotel transactions?
Anything on the blockchain?
Yeah, I mean a blockchain is just a just
a ledger. Um there's plenty of ledgers
kind of out there and in Japan in
particular, people business case for for
let's just take the hospitality industry
in which we're very familiar. Is there a
business case for that for accepting and
you know using transactions on on you
know on chain? I mean yes and no. You
know in Japan now people are very
familiar with using electronic money. So
you can go to the hotel and you can tap
your phone. In states you can use Apple
Pay to to settle transactions. Um I
think for a consumer what's most
important is the speed of the
transaction. And I did in the early
days, you know, try to pay for a coffee
with Bitcoin and you're standing there
for 15 minutes waiting for the
transaction to confirm. And you know, in
its current form, it isn't a great
money. It doesn't need to be a great
money. It's a wonderful store of value.
And there may be, you know, applications
that are built on Bitcoin in the future
that enable these kind of microp
payments. I know there are a few. I even
use them. But as a as a company, as a
hotel company or any business to accept
Bitcoin as payment is is really clever,
right? you can begin to grow your
Bitcoin holdings over time. Don't sell
it, keep it. It's a great way to, you
know, to start to diversify out of the
the cash that you're that you're
receiving. Um, but you know, most
companies, they need that money that
they've earned from revenue to pay
expenses. And so, if you're a hotel
company, your margins are razor thin.
It's why I'm so happy now that I'm out
of the hospitality industry. But those
razor thin margins don't really enable
you to to keep that revenue. Even if it
came in Bitcoin, you'd have to sell it
to to pay expenses. But more and more
companies, I think out of um around the
world will begin to accept Bitcoin for
payment, be possible to to transact
purely in Bitcoin. Um certainly in in
the Middle East now, you're seeing
people use Bitcoin to purchase cars,
they purchase apartments. Um so the
sellers are smart. They're like, I I
like this pristine capital.
I want to go back to after co. So when
Michael Sailor was talking about how he
started this strategy, he was saying,
you know, how co hit and then um the
company was competing with other
companies like M um Microsoft.
What was your story like?
Well, at that time
I wish I had a a more complicated story
to be honest. You know, we we were
struggling a lot at that time. Our
hotels were forcibly closed. And so we
were in four markets, three in Southeast
Asia and Japan. And three of those four
markets, we were told that our hotel had
to be closed. And so there was just, you
know, zero revenue and the expenses were
still there. And so we're in that
existential moment of how do we survive
this? and our auditor had put this going
concern footnote in our financials which
basically auditors do when you don't
have enough cash to survive 12 months
and so it was really it was it was a
tough time um and inspired by the words
of of Michael Sailor and um I think I
used a lot of the information that he
had shared as ammo in my own kind of
board meeting discussions and people
were very receptive uh they said let's
let's convene a shareholder meeting and
ask our shareholders and so We went
through the, you know, the process of
that. We announced that we'd have a
shareholder meeting. We announced what
the agenda items would be. We announced
that we would be buying Bitcoin and
making that our core treasury asset. And
the market immediately responded. So
that made us feel more confident that
that was the path to to go down. And now
we're only, you know, 13 14 months into
the story. And um I'm feel excited and
um you know, eager to to continue with
this pace of growth. And there's a very
high hurdle and expectations now that
are placed on us. Um, but I'm up to the
task. How did the story go? So, were you
buying Bitcoin before this happened? No.
And you just came across on YouTube or
how does that work? Right. Well, you
mean personally? Well, you have to first
believe in Bitcoin and this strategy to,
you know, proceed, right? How did that
story go? Sure. Well, I I purchased
Bitcoin actually early on um back in end
of 2012 2013 on Mount Gaus living in
Japan at that time. And you know, that's
how a lot of people who were kind of
early buyers of Bitcoin first got their
exposure. Um and so I suppose I've been
a a Bitcoiner, you know, for some time.
It was something that kept me sane while
I was part of the hotel business. And
every time I wanted to cry because there
was some issue in, you know, in the
hotel business, I could I could think
about Bitcoin. Um and so yeah, really
looking for a path for many years on how
I could bring my side passion together
with business and that opportunity
presented itself at the depth of co
I believe you said once and I'm
paraphrasing that Bitcoin is a moral
imperative. What do you mean by that?
I think I may have said it was sort of a
moral obligation obligation myself and
others in the industry to help others
discover Bitcoin. And so in Japan right
now, if you discover Bitcoin, it's just
not a really easy way to get exposure.
Prior to Metapon, it wasn't an easy way
to get exposure. The complexity and
opening up a an account. Um, you know,
Japan increased its regulation
significantly post Mount Gaus, which is
which is a great thing and had to be
done. Um, but a lot of that regulation
from those old days remains today. So,
it's uh it's not easy often to um to be
involved in the the digital asset space.
Um, and so we, you know, we we came
about and we recognized that we wanted
to provide exposure to Japanese
investors that wanted to buy Bitcoin and
found a way for them to achieve that in
a very taxefficient manner. Now, beyond
beyond that, you know, we have the the
license for Bitcoin magazine in Japan.
We launched our first edition uh back in
March. The next one comes out at the end
of June and we're using that as our way
to onboard Japanese people into Bitcoin.
We feel that we have an obligation, a
moral obligation to um to educate people
on Bitcoin, help them with financial
literacy. And so the Bitcoin magazine um
is intended not to be a massive money
maker, but really to to be a tool um for
us to explain uh the story of Bitcoin.
We also have our hotel. We sold
everything except for one. And so the
last um remaining hotel is going to be
rebranded as the Bitcoin hotel. And
again that is our you know opportunity
to on people onboard people in real
life. People can come they can
experience the hotel. They can uh go to
the Bitcoin art museum and we'll be
working with Bitcoin artists around the
world that want to build on Bitcoin and
have their art there. And we'll have a
Bitcoin museum. People like to learn
about the history of Bitcoin. Uh there
may be a Satoshi Nakamoto waxed figure
kind of in the lobby that they can take
photos with. And of course, we'd be
honored if you guys would come and and
visit the hotel when we open the
beginning of next year. How much orange
will be used in the decor?
Good question. Is there too much orange?
Is that possible? I will ask the
interior designers. It sounds like
Bitcoin conference every day. Yeah. The
hotel. Yeah. Except you sleep in the in
the in the room. Simon, what's next for
MetaPlanet? You've adopted the strategy
that has worked for you. you turned the
company around. Uh like Monty said, 600k
Bitcoin premium. It's working. Um any
advancements to your strategy? Any
expansion plans now that you have one
hotel? Do you plan to buy more hotels?
Uh no. No. No. Uh the reason we have the
hotel is it's left over from the old
days. Yeah. Um and so as we're keeping
it and you know there's a number of
reasons why we want to maintain the
hotel. The most important is that we
have a lot of tax losses that are
attached to the hotel. So, as long as
you keep it, you can use those tax
losses and offset that against future
gains from from other businesses. So, it
it it's it's quite valuable for us to
keep. But apart from the hotel, you
know, we are 100% a Bitcoin company now.
And the brilliant thing about a Bitcoin
treasury company, there's no need to to
really innovate. you have your core
business which is to buy Bitcoin and
where the innovation um you know resides
is in the ways that you raise capital
and so our primary form of capital
raising now is you know the moving
strike warrants the at the money equity
offering um look alike yeah uh just to
follow up so what do you think of
companies that use a hybrid strategy so
at one point I mean Elon Musk sold most
of um Bitcoin for Tesla but at one point
Tesla did hold bitcoins on their
treasury as well um for maybe different
reasons than you and obviously their
core business is not to be a Bitcoin
treasury company. So should any company
with core operations outside of a
treasury holding company acquire Bitcoin
to be held on their treasury treasury as
a cash alternative? Absolutely. I think
why
I mean for the same reasons why we've
discussed owning Bitcoin makes sense. I
think we want to have not just cash
sitting there and cash sitting there is
is depreciating in value. I know some
companies in Asia, they they hold gold
on their balance sheet and Bitcoin, I
think, is a much better version of gold.
It's a digital gold and so it should be
in every CFO's, you know, treasure chest
of things to select from. Yes. It
shouldn't just be cash.
Can I have one last question? One last
question. The producer said one one. I
was talking to um an owner of an
exchange from Asia the other day. So he
said the US may have already won the
Bitcoin war because everything is priced
in USD stable coins. Does that mean
other countries are now too far behind?
I think adoption will take time. Um I
also think that America is much smarter
than people give it credit for. So I
think Bitcoin is being purchased behind
the scenes and just not being
telegraphed. Right? if if the US
announces every single purchase that it
makes um that would be working against
it, right? Price would go up a lot and
they wouldn't be able to buy as much as
they would like. Um but there are many
nation states that are publicly
disclosing that they're buying Bitcoin.
El Salvador, I think, is a is a perfect
example. Uh Bhutan um is doing the same.
I know in the Middle East there are many
nations which are buying Bitcoin and
they're announcing in different forms.
And so I think there's room for many
Bitcoin superpowers. The US definitely
is is the biggest and baddest superpower
out there. Um, but those that follow in
due course, I think they can also be a
Bitcoin superpower. And you know, we
want to in Japan kind of help Japan
become that. Right now, it's through,
you know, Metaplanet. And we're the
largest holder of Bitcoin now, you know,
as a as a corporation in Japan and and
also in Asia. And we hope to do our part
in inspiring Japan perhaps to follow in
Japan's follow in the US's footsteps.
So, um I wouldn't be too disappointed
that you're not seeing it happen kind of
everywhere. It all takes time and you
should be pleased that there is more
time for you and I and others to buy
Bitcoin before it becomes unaffordable.
I love that. Well, uh let's make Bitcoin
affordable for everybody. Thank you for
disseminating your
That's not what I meant. I meant one day
we'll all be rich enough to be buying as
much Bitcoin as we want. That's the
dream. You have to tell all your friends
and your family and those you care about
that Bitcoin is now the time to buy.
This is why you're on the show because
you can give the message much better
than I can. Thank you so much. It was a
pleasure to be here. Thank you very much
for having me. Thank you. help you.